

2600 Gramercy Street, Houston TX, 77030

🛘 +1 (360) 213 - 6063 | 🔀 WillSu@WilliamSu.me | 🏕 www.WilliamSu.me | 🖸 WillSu88 | 🛅 WillSu88

Summary_

Motivated CS student with experiences in machine learning, reactive web & iOS app development, and database management. Comfortable working in a software team environment, speaking to clients, and managing products through agile life cycles. Currently open to summer 2020 internships that can leverage my skills as a software engineer.

Education

Rice University Houston TX, USA

MASTER OF COMPUTER SCIENCE & BACHELOR OF ARTS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

- RiceApps Software Developer
- Academic Fellow for COMP 215 Intro to Program Design
- Vice President for Rice Taiwanese Association
- · Courses: Models for Data Science, Parallel Programming, Linear Algebra, Computer Systems
- GPA: 3.72/4.00

Experiences

Expero Inc. Houston TX, USA

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN - EDGE ML ON FPGA TEAM

May 2019 - July 2019

- Trained a fully-connected neural network with Keras achieving an 80% accuracy in anamoly detection.
- Remodeled the neural network to be FPGA-compatible through post-quantizing its weights.
- Developed experiments in C and Xilinx Vivado to validate neural network logic written in Verilog for the FPGA.

Lam Research Corporation

Shanghai, China

Aug. 2017 - May. 2021

DATA SCIENCE INTERN - CSBG DEPARMENT

June 2018 - Aug. 2018

- Created Python scripts to automate daily data ETL process, reducing time up to 2 hours a day.
- Redesigned data exploration operations by implementing temporary databases in SQLite.
- Visualized weekly sales and machine usage data through Matplotlib, Seaborn, and QlikSense.

Projects

Github **News Sentiment to Stock**

- Engineered multiple sentiment analysis techniques for news articles to predict stock prices.
- Built a bag-of-words model that outperforms Apache's NLTK in stock prediction.

Github Hedwig

- Developed 2 iOS campus-food delivery apps with React Native, GraphQL, and mLab.
- Consolidated payment security & improved inventory management by integrating Stripe.
- · Wireframed the apps' UI using Invision Studio.

Github What's My Next Book

- Implemented & analyzed 4 different book recommender systems.
- Trained models in parallel on the cloud using Jupyter, Keras, and AWS EC2.

Skills_

Programming Python · Java · C · Bash · Latex

ML / Data Keras · Pandas · Numpy · SQL · GraphQL

Front-End React · MobX · HTML5 · CSS · Javascript · InVision

DevOps Git · AWS · Docker · Apache Nifi **Languages** English · Mandarin · Taiwanese **Interests** Basketball · Photography · Meditation

WILLIAM SU · RÉSUMÉ JULY 15, 2019